# Keletso Maleka

## Mechanical Engineer/ Data scientist

I am a Mechanical Engineering graduate from the University of Pretoria, I am currently a Data science Intern at Explore Data science academy where I am learning data science skills and how to apply it in a business environment. I am a cheerful person, I approach each situation or challenge with optimism and a positive attitude. My goal is to learn as much as I can and apply that knowledge.

I am a self motivated and and energetic individual who is committed to giving his best in everything he does. I have good communication skills. My experience as a Data Scientist at Explore Software has enabled me to improve my analytical and problem solving skills.

## Get in touch!

#### LinkedIn:

www.linkedin.com/in/keletsomaleka-8288b490

#### Mobile:

067 406 1717

#### Fmail:

keletsomaleka@yahoo.co.za

#### **Address:**

39 Harrison Street , Benoni, 1501

#### **Drivers license:**

Code B

# Work Experience

### **Data Science Intern**

### Explore Data Science Academy. | January 2020- Present

- My team worked on a project for a Kenyan e-commerce company whereby we were tasked with developing a machine learning model that predicts the time from pickup to arrival for their deliveries.
- I completed a natural language processing competition on Zindi where I achieved a 16th place position out of 187 contestants.
- Most of the projects I participated in required use of python programming, SQL and Power BI which really improved my technical skills.

## **Mechanical Engineering Student**

Mercedes-Benz (SA) | Dec 2014 - Jan 2015

- · Help in defining a specification sheet for new vehicle model.
- Worked on a government tender and helped to successfully complete the project without any discrepancies.

### Education

## **Bachelor of Engineering in Mechanical engineering**

University of Pretoria Duration: 2014 - 2019

- Design project: Design of a Multi- Axis machine Tool.
- Research Project: Designing and building of a solar tracker using arduino.

#### Data science certificate

#### **Explore Data Science Academy**

**Duration: 2014 - 2019** 

- · Agile project management framework
- AWS

### Skills

- Python programming
- Data analytics
- Data mining
- Machine learning
- Solidworks ,CAD
- SQL, PowerBI, pipelines
- web scraping
- Arduino, raspberry pi
- MS Excel, powerpoint, word